# Jon Phoenix

# Brand Designer and Front-End Web Developer based in the Emerald City.

jon@jonphoenix.com

github.com/JonPhoenix

linkedin.com/in/jonphoenix

# **Professional Summary**

Extensive experience across Europe and the Americas developing brand identity and consumer packaging for leading global companies. During my career, I have led several high-visibility projects for top multinational enterprises such as Procter & Gamble, Johnson & Johnson, Pernod Ricard, Nespresso, and The Coca-Cola Company. I have eclectic experience leading teams and fostering a creative atmosphere across diverse environments.

Other achievements include: Hosted the Landor 2012 International Forum of Design; selected as an attendee for the Festival of Creativity in Cannes; honored as invited speaker at conferences and awarded at the *a! Diseño* Awards Ceremony in 2016 and 2017.

Currently working as an independent UX/UI designer, expanding my technical knowledge in the digital world with a certificate in Full-Stack Web Development at UW.

# **Experience**

# Independent Brand Designer and Consultant for The Legacy®. Seattle WA | August 2019 - Present

My role as an independent brand consultant is to expand the company's eminence and business upon relocating to Seattle. My main contributions are:

- Curating design cases for The Legacy®'s portfolio of work —online and offline
- · Reviewing presentations for strategic projects and key business leads
- Leading brand strategies to elevate The Legacy®'s market prestige
- Leading promotional initiatives for print and digital media
- Presenting brand design trends to key clients

## Partner, Creative Director at The Legacy\*. Mexico City, Mexico | October 2013 - July 2019

I generated a positive impact inside the company's culture and its business growth; ensured excellency in design execution while managing and mentoring a creative team of fifteen. I successfully developed projects for The Coca-Cola Company, Johnson and Johnson, Dannon, and several new business leads. My contributions also included:

- Signing off on projects for presentations and keeping deadlines
- Promoting the values of the agency internally and externally
- Providing insight on design trends and branding culture
- Featuring brand strategy in every project, small or big
- Maintaining an excellent relationship with clients

## Creative Director at Landor Associates. Mexico City, Mexico | August 2012 - August 2013

I was the leader of the packaging design and the graphic production teams for Latin American markets. Efficiently managed competing workstreams, worked under tight deadlines, and collaborated crossfunctionally with the client service and the strategic planning departments. Also successfully provided:

- Creative solutions for Procter & Gamble, PepsiCo, Starbucks, Danone and Diageo
- Outstanding work engaging new business prospects and talent for the company
- Confidently presented Landor's work to senior clients and top decision makers

#### Independent Design Director. Paris, France | September 2011 - August 2012

An entrepreneurial year developing projects for clients in Mexico, France and the UAE:

- For Futurebrand of Paris, I developed premium projects for Martell, Rémy Martin, and Nespresso
- I consulted with The Legacy® for projects in connection with Mondelèz and Walmart of Mexico
- From my home studio I worked with CB'a Design of Dubai, Lipton Tea and Harvest Foods

#### Design Director at CB'a Design. Paris, France | August 2008 - September 2011

Based at the headquarters in Paris, France and also collaborated at the office in Milan, Italy. I created and implemented strategic direction in packaging projects for several brands and markets, such as:

- · Joseph Perrier, Dulux Valentine (Akzo Nobel), Schweppes, and Imperial Tobacco in France
- Lipton Tea and Lipton Ice Tea in Europe, Middle East and the Americas
- Ferrero and Nestlé in Italy, Elbisco in Greece, and Lu in Finland

# Sr. Designer at Landor Associates. Paris, France | October 2005 - July 2008

Relocated to Paris as a member of the multicultural creative team, taking on additional responsibilities leading design teams, working with clients in three languages on a daily basis:

- · Mövenpick of Switzerland, Philip Morris International (now Altria Group) and Pernod Ricard
- · My work for Europe was launched in France, Spain, Italy, Belgium, Croatia and Switzerland
- Also in Turkey, Tunisia, Algeria, Russia, China, UAE, Mexico and Latin American countries

#### Designer / Sr. Designer at Landor Associates. Mexico City, Mexico | February 2001 - September 2005

I began my professional career working as a packaging designer for this first-tier branding company. My achievements included:

- Successful projects for Modelo Brewery, Frito-Lay, Danone, and Philip Morris (now Altria Group)
- · An early promotion to manage my own team of three designers, dedicated to high-profile clients
- Designer ambassador traveling to collaborate with the offices in New York City, London, and Paris
- First graphic designer in the Mexico City office to win monumental Landor Award in 2003

# **Professional Volunteer Contributions**

# University of Michigan Alumni Association of Seattle | April 2020

Seattle chapter 2020 T-shirt original design and final production artwork

# Languages

- English Fluent
- French Fluent, native speaker
- Spanish Fluent, native speaker

#### Education

#### Degrees:

#### Universidad Autónoma Metropolitana, Mexico City. Mexico

Bachelor's Degree. Graphic Communication Design. 1996 - 2001

#### Certifications:

## University of Washington. Seattle WA. USA

Certificate in Web Development. Anticipated completion November 2020

#### Pyramid Étapes, Paris. France

Certificate in Graphic Production, 2011

#### Universidad Iberoamericana, Mexico City. Mexico

Certificate in Leadership and Coaching. 2004

## Moorgate Institute, Paris. France

Presentation Skills Workshop. 2007

Guggenheim Museum.

# **Awards**

- First National Student Art Competition. May 1993. SEP (Mexican Secretariat of Public Education)
   + Fila-Dixon® Group. Awarded Second Place among hundreds of submissions in a ceremony presided by federal government authorities and members of the art community, such as the prominent painter Jose Luis Cuevas†. The committee selected me for delivering the acceptance speech on behalf of all awarded students. My painting was exhibited at the National Palace of Fine Arts in Mexico City, and traveled to New York City to visit the Metropolitan Museum and the
- Title: "1985" / Technique: Oil and acrylics on wood. / Subject: Heroics of ordinary citizens helping each other in the wake of a magnitude 8.1 earthquake devastating Mexico City in September 1985.

- a! Diseño. Packaging Design Award / April 2017 / Saladena Cheese. USA
- a! Diseño. Packaging Design Award / April 2016 / Danone Danonino. Mexico
- a! Diseño. Packaging Design Award / April 2016 / Alouette Spreadable Cheese. USA
- Landor Associates Award / Mexico City Office / July 2003

# **Professional Skills**

# Branding, Design and Consulting:

- Branding and Identity
- Packaging Design
- Advanced Sketching / Storyboard
- Creative Process, Design Process, Implementation Process
- Concept Development Packaging, Retail and OOH
- Graphic Production Process
- Team Leadership
- · Client Management
- Presentation Skills

## Full Stack Web Development (In Progress):

- Computer Science applied to JavaScript
- Browser Based Technologies and Command Line
- Databases and Server Development
- Quality Assurance Process

## **Technical Skills**

- MacOs Catalina Windows 10
- Adobe® Creative Cloud
- Apple iWork Microsoft Office Wordpress
- HTML / CSS / JavaScript / Node.js / UX & UI / Databases

# **Featured Web Projects**

#### **Breakaway**

Breakaway is an app that increases productivity by helping create a culture and community of taking breaks. Managers can track employee PTO and employees can share experiences with this fun and seamless user experience.

Technologies: JavaScript / MySQL / Sequelize / Heroku & JawsDB / Handlebars / UI Design

# **Discover Serenity**

A web application that provides its users with the best hiking trail options in the United States, avoiding crowds and therefore easier to find serenity outdoors. Reliable information featuring fewer health risks.

Users can start s search by input their city or zip code or their location.

Technologies: JavaScript / HTML / CSS / Semantic UI / jQuery / APIs / UI Design

#### **Thunder Burger**

Thunder Burger is a restaurant app where burger lovers can order their favorite burgers and devour them as fast as one click. A restaurant business using this application will be able to keep track of burgers being ordered, devoured and removed from the burger slate.

Technologies: JavaScript / HTML / CSS / MySQL / Heroku & JawsDB / Handlebars / UI Design

#### **Da Vinci Coder**

A password generator app that seeks to provide a strongly reliable service for users looking to protect the access to sensitive data. By randomly generating a password that meets specific criteria, the app user will be able to create a strong secure password.

Technologies: JavaScript / HTML / CSS / Responsive design across viewports

#### **SunnyMoon Weather**

A weather dashboard app with a powerful search functionality to find the current weather conditions, and the future weather outlook for any city in the world. The user will be able to plan a personal trip or a business trip based on the displayed data and keep the searched cities for future reference.

Technologies: JavaScript / HTML / CSS / APIs / Responsive design across viewports